congratulations you are the last four
artists standing between the four of you
we've won every elimination tattoo
you've been neck and neck the entire
competition but that's all about to
change there's only one of you can earn
$100,000 a feature in Inked Magazine and
the title of ink master I don't think
that in any point in tattooing I've ever
felt as much pressure to perform if I
don't make it into the final three I'd
be devastated this week you'll be judged
on all of the essential skills precision
contrast detail proportion dimension
everything you need to be a master
tattoo artist there are no more flash
challenges there is also no human canvas
jury and the winner will not put an
artist up now on it's all completely up
to the judges if I stumble just a little
bit I could go home and all of this will
be for naught some of the most
meaningful tattoos celebrate a personal
victory one of the greatest triumphs is
surviving cancer your canvases today
have all survived one of the deadliest
forms breast cancer many of them beat
cancer by having a mastectomy to remove
the breast some women choose to
reconstruct their breasts but the scars
remain and these scars aren't a very
sensitive area so it's even more
challenging to pull off a flawless
tattoo that's exactly what you must do
these canvases
as a cancer survivor I know what it's
like to stare death in the face this
tattoo represents life and it represents
the good things that come out of
fighting not about the biggest tattoo
the biggest tattoo is not gonna win this
is something that's very personal to
these ladies in a delicate area
this is really a big part of doing what
we do is working with our canvases
it's not about you it's about them we
care that you give them what they want
let's meet your canvases
[Music]
today we have to do the most important
tattoo that we've ever had to do it's
one of the only tattoos you can give
somebody that actually helps change
their life because there's no flash
challenge the human canvases will be
randomly assigned canvases one by one
please choose a skull to determine your
artist
[Music]
hello
Maddie you have the rest of the night to
consult with your campuses tomorrow
you'll have six hours to tattoo based on
your work one
we'll be packing your machines good luck
these canvases are looking for great
work out of these Final Four artists and
that's what we're hoping for as well
this is a way to not only commemorate
what they've been through but to
beautify it these guys need to really
step off to give them everything they
can my idea was a dandelion on the side
blowing across transforming into
butterflies I hope that getting this
tattoo is really going to make me feel
like I have my life back
cancer doesn't owe me I know I'm very
scary you just put your faith in me I'm
gonna give you a beautiful tattoo it's
gonna be a breeze like say we're working
right in here your scar my mom died from
breast cancer and then flowers on the
other side I want a flowering vine
across the whole chest you trying to go
where the nipples would tend to be or
okay I feel like a war went on in my
chest this is like a battlefield and I
would rather have something beautiful
it's just a stray shoulders and
everything glory stars are not
symmetrical this one you're really
really round here a little bit concave
on this one so I have to take a
different plan of action what I'm gonna
try to do is just make sure that
whatever we place over here lays evenly
there's not gonna be a symmetry between
the two pieces it's a risk I could be in
trouble
you